ARPITA DESHMUKH

Dallas, TX | H1-B Visa (Active from Oct 2021) arpitapd@tamu.edu|<u>linkedin.com/in/arpitapd</u>

ABOUT ME

I'm an eager learner & a passionate data engineer with 3+ years of experience in Behavioral Healthcare including business analysis, advanced analytical skills, and SQL. Skilled in data manipulation, analyzing complex data sets with 1 million+ rows, integrating complex systems, and ensuring high data quality for real-time reporting.

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University, Mays Business School (MS in Management Information Systems) College Station, TX Aug 2018 - May 2020 University of Pune (Bachelor's in Information Technology) Pune, India Aug 2014 - May 2018

SKILLS

Languages & other Skills: SQL | Python | Healthcare | Agile | ETL | Git | HDFS commands | Data warehouse | Shell Tools: Alteryx | PowerBI | RDBMS | SQL Server | SSIS | SSRS | SSAS | NoSQL | AWS (S3, EC2, Redshift, Kinesis, AWS Athena, RDS, elastic beanstalk) | Airflow | Spark

EXPERIENCE

Behavioral Health Group, LLC (BI Data Engineer)

Dallas, TX Jan 2022 - Present

- Collaborated with C-suite executives and other stakeholders to capture requirements, identify trends, enable data-driven decisions by performing end-to-end process from ETL to reporting
- Built and maintained automated data pipelines using Alteryx, SQL to collect, integrate data from multiple data sources; built insightful PowerBI reports with accurate and consistent data, improving operational decisions significantly
- Automated process of data extraction, transformation, backing up and uploading report to HR system via SMTP on daily basis, replacing human intervention completely
- Developed relevant Metrics, KPIs for monitoring counselor and supervisor performances for 120+ global locations
- Created SQL queries involving complex joins and window functions, improving data retrieval by 15%

Behavioral Health Group, LLC (Revenue Data Analyst)

Dallas, TX July 2020 - Jan 2022

- Expedited data pipeline by replacing normal functionality to In-DB process in Alteryx, reducing execution time by 80%
- Patient No Show Project Utilized SQL CTEs, windows function, joins to populate data of over 7 million rows, PowerBI report generation to track patients with missed doses and no-show follow-up calls, enabling improvement in patient care

Strategic Materials, Inc (Data & Business Intelligence Analyst Intern)

Houston, TX May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Conducted requirements elicitation from C-suite executives, and stakeholders for creating real-time interactive dashboards.
- **Tracking on-Time shipments** -Created BI dashboard to compare on-time shipments percentage across global facilities for past 6 months; incorporated email alert system if on-time percentage falls below 70% for the current month.

BIG DATA PERSONAL PROJECTS

Reports to strategize new product launch in Healthcare Sector Spark | ETL | Amazon S3 | Azure Blob | HDFS | Python

• Created an automated data pipeline involving data ingestion using spark data frame, transformations and loading data in S3, Azure blob and PostgreSQL; successfully deployed project on single node cluster on Google cloud.